Selected Compositions of Harry Benjamin Jepson
Yale University Music Library
Selected Compositions of Harry Benjamin Jepson;
1870-1979
1909-1923
Misc. Ms. 216
Yale University Music Library
1.5
(1 box)
Music by the American composer and organist Harry Benjamin Jepson (1870-1952)
Jepson, Harry Benjamin, 1870-1952
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was established in the Music Library of Yale University by Harvey P. Russell in 1979.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by title.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of holograph sketches and scores and published editions of 14 of Jepson's musical compositions, primarily organ music.
Biographical / Historical
Harry Benjamin Jepson was born in New Haven, Connecticut on August 16, 1870. He attended Yale University, earning the B.A. in 1893 and the B.M. in 1894; his teachers included Horatio Parker and Gustave Stoeckel. Later he also studied in Paris with Charles Marie Widor and Louis Vierne. In 1895 he was appointed instructor at Yale; he was promoted to assistant professor in 1899, university organist in 1906, and full professor in 1907. He also directed the choir in the university's Battell Chapel. Jepson was known for his organ compositions as well as his performances. He retired in 1939, and died in Noank, Connecticut on August 23, 1952.
Organ music; Sonatas (Organ)
- [Ballade] Ballade for organ / [New York]: G. Schirmer, c1907., (10 p.) 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  General
  Holograph in ink.
  On t.p.: To Florence Annette Wells. Lewiston - Me.
  Publisher's copy with markings. Notes clipped to pages 4 and 7.
- Carnaval, Score (19 p.) 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Holograph in pencil with corrections.
  For orchestra.
- [Etude] Etude for the organ / [New York]: G. Schirmer, c1923., (12 p.) 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  On t.p.: To L.U.E.
  Publisher's copy with markings.
- [Idylle] Idylle: L'Heure exquise for organ, Jun. 1915; (13 p.) 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  On t.p.: To Ruth Muzzy. Idylle (L'Heure exquise) for organ. Composed by Harry Benjamin Jepson. June 15 - New Haven.
  L'Heure exquise and La Chevelure are written in pencil below the title.
- Masquerade, [c1923]; (12 p.) 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Holograph in ink-and pencil with corrections.
  For organ.
- [Pantomime] Pantomime: Pierrot and Columbine for organ, Aug. 1915; (8 p.) 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Holograph in ink and pencil.
  On t.p.: Pantomime (Pierrot and Columbine) for organ. Composed by Harry Benjamin Jepson. August 1915 - Norwalk, Ct.
- [Papillons Noirs] Papillons Noirs fot the organ, c1923; (4 p.) 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Holograph in ink and pencil with corrections.
  On t.p.: To Samuel A. Baldwin. Professor of Music - College of the City of New York.
- [Papillons Noirs] Papillons Noirs for the organ / [New York]: G. Schirmer, c1923., (4 p.) 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  On t.p.: To Samuel A. Baldwin.
- [Pastel] Pastel for organ, Jan. 1915; (8 p.) 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  On t.p.: Pastel for organ composed by H.B. Jepson. January 1915 - New Haven.
- Pierrot. Sketch., score (6 p.) 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Holograph in pencil.
- [Sonata, organ, no. 1. Sketches] Sonata in G minor for organ / [New York: H.W. Gray, c1913], (56, (18) p.) 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Corrections appear next to errors made in movement numberings.
- [Sonata, organ, no. 2] Second sonata for the organ, 1919; (11, (3), 10) 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  On t.p.: To Eric De Lemarter. Chicago, Ill. This composition won the prize offered by Mr. Eric De Lemarter of Chicago in 1919 for the Best Sonata - Orchestral Style.
  Publisher's copy with markings. New York: H.W. Gray, c1921.
  Incomplete copy. Movement II, "Les Jongleurs," is missing.
- [Sonata, organ, no. 2. Zingara. Sketch] Zingara, 1919; (3 p.) 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- A Song: Chanson Triste: L'Allée est sans fin., Piano-vocal score (3 p.) 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Veni, Sancte Spiritus. Sketch / [New York: H.W. Gray, c1909], (1 p.) 33 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Version of the hymn by Robertus, Galliae Rex araanged for (TTBB). English translation by C.H. Zimmerman.
- We part tonight, Jepson, Benjamin; 5 p. 24 cm. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  On t.p.: We Part To-night, song and chorus arranged for the class of 1913, New Haven High School, by B. Jepson, Supervisor of Music, New Haven Public Schools.
  Published version, publisher and date unknown.
  For chorus (SATB) and keyboard instrument.
- Jepson, Benjamin, 1870?; Photo. 12.5 x 17.3 cm., mounted. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Russell, Harvey R., 2 leaves. 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Autograph letter signed, 1979 Sep. 3, Bloomfield, N.J., to Harold Samuels, New Haven, Connecticut.
  Photocopy.
  Relates to and was enclosed with the items listed above.
- Re Jepson's organ recitals in Woolsey Hall. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  11 clippings. 1909, n.d.
  Added Aug. 1982